[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is Java?",
    "answers": [
      "A scripting language",
      "An operating system",
      "A programming language",
      "A markup language"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which keyword is used to declare a class in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "class",
      "int",
      "declare",
      "Class"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the main purpose of the `public static void main(String[] args)` method in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "To print \"Hello, World!\"",
      "To declare variables",
      "To define a class",
      "Entry point for the Java program"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which data type is used to store whole numbers in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "float",
      "double",
      "int",
      "char"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "How do you instantiate an object in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "new Object()",
      "Object.create()",
      "create Object",
      "Object.newInstance()"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What is the Java keyword used for inheritance?",
    "answers": [
      "inherit",
      "extends",
      "implements",
      "inheritance"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which loop is used when you want to execute a block of code at least once, even if the condition is false from the beginning?",
    "answers": [
      "for loop",
      "while loop",
      "do-while loop",
      "if-else loop"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the purpose of the `break` statement in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "To exit the program",
      "To terminate a loop",
      "To skip the current iteration",
      "To print a message"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which method is used to obtain the length of an array in Java?",
    "answers": [
      "arraySize()",
      "getSize()",
      "lengthOfArray()",
      "length()"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "In Java, what is the difference between `==` and `.equals()` when comparing strings?",
    "answers": [
      "They are used interchangeably",
      "`==` compares references, `.equals()` compares content",
      "Both compare content",
      "Both compare references"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  }
]
